

Kingsley Raspe

Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer

CONTACT

(cellphone removed)
hello@kingsley.sh
kingsley.sh
github.com/kingsloi
linkedin.com/in/kingsleyraspe

British Nationality
US Green Card Holder

SKILLS

Node.js, Laravel, Vue.js, Nuxt.js AWS (S3, SES, EC2, LB, RDS) Serverless (Lambda) CI/CD High Availability Babel/Webpack/Transpiling PHPUnit/Cypress

LANGUAGES

Javascript (ES6+)

PHP

HTML5/HTML

SCSS/CSS

Bash/Shell Scripting

Linux

Git/GitLab

MySQL, MongoDB

PROFILE

A full stack web developer and DevOps engineer with 11+ years experience, specialising in a broad range of open-source tech, including Node.js/Express.js, PHP8/Laravel, JavaScript/Vue.js, SCSS, Webpack, CI/CD, and more. Passionate about writing highly available, clean, maintainable, and testable code. Originally from the UK, now residing in the beautiful lake-side city of Gary, Indiana.

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer

Plinqit (remote, USA) | Feb 2023 - Present

Michgan-based fintech startup whose mission is promoting financial wellness.

- Using HubSpot's REST API, developed a custom HubSpot CRM implementation into the Plinqit platform
- Architected and developed a containerised Laravel REST API to communicate with a new Plinqit product, integrating into many different 3rd party banking-related applications, and services

Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer (Systems Support Analyst)

Pearson (remote, USA) | May 2017 - Feb 2023

Pearson, the world's leading learning company.

- Remotely supported an entire fleet of AWS infrastructure, maintaining ~50 websites
- Built tools in many languages around lead generation, including a complete form builder & lead API in Laravel, ES6, Nunjucks, and a prerendering service (Node.js, Express.js, Puppeteer, Lambda, SQS) to convert WordPress sites into static HTML



Kingsley Raspe

Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer

CONTACT

(cellphone removed)
hello@kingsley.sh
kingsley.sh
github.com/kingsloi
linkedin.com/in/kingsleyraspe

British Nationality
US Green Card Holder

SKILLS

Node.js, Laravel, Vue.js, Nuxt.js
AWS (S3, SES, EC2, LB, RDS)
Serverless (Lambda)
CI/CD
High Availability
Babel/Webpack/Transpiling
PHPUnit/Cypress

LANGUAGES

Javascript (ES6+)

PHP

HTML5/HTML

SCSS/CSS

Bash/Shell Scripting

Linux

Git/GitLab

MySQL, MongoDB

WORK HISTORY

Director / Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer

Forwardslash Consulting Ltd (remote, UK) | January 2014 - May 2017

Worked as a digital nomad through Forwardslash Consulting Ltd in the UK, operating as a full stack web developer, working with clients around the world, including the Dubai, Australia, and Europe, developing single-page websites, bespoke CRM applications, inventory management systems, and everything in between.

eLearning Consultant / Web Developer

Phones4u (Stafford, UK) | July 2013 - August 2014

Developed a series of internal micro sites/applications to help Phones 4u's 5000 retail staff digest daily/weekly/monthly content from leadership, partners, new tech, regulatory info, etc.

Web Developer Intern

The Grossbauer Group (Indiana, USA) | August 2011 - August 2012

Underwent a 12 month international internship as front/backend developer.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) International Web Development — Grade 2:1

Staffordshire University, Stafford (UK) | 2010 - 2013

HND Applied Information Technology

Staffordshire University, Lichfield (UK) | 2008 - 2010

BTEC National Diploma in Applied Information Technology

Tamworth and Lichfield College, Tamworth (UK) | 2006 - 2008